Hula, Erich; Papers ger044
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Erich Hula Papers
1900-1986
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Hula, Erich, 1900-
ger044
22 cubic ft.
A substantial portion of the Erich Hula Papers consists of his writings, both in typescript and published form. This includes his contributions to newspapers and journals as well as extensive notes from his research and for courses taught. The collection also contains correspondence files and biographical documents, and a large collection of reprints (and some typescripts) sent to and collected by Hula of colleagues and other scholars.
Biographical Sketch
According to Arnold Brecht, a contemporary of Hula at the New School for Social Research, Erich Hula was "one of the most influential colleagues in the administrative and scholarly development of the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research, which he joined in 1938 after his arrival as a fugitive from Nazi-occupied Austria". With the exception of a semester at Cornell University (Spring 1953) and a year at the Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research of The Johns Hopkins University (1957/1958), Hula spent his entire teaching career, from 1938 until 1967, at the New School, where he also served continuously from 1942 until retirement on the editorial board of Social Research as well as a two-year term as Dean of the Graduate Faculty from 1948-1950.
Erich Hula was born in Vienna, Austria on May 27, 1900, where he also received his formal education in jurisprudence and political science. Hula studied under Hans Kelsen and was awarded a Doctor of Law degree from the University of Vienna in 1924. Hula was able to continue his studies from 1927 to 1930 in England, France and the United States under a Rockefeller grant. After completion of his studies, Hula was once again taken under the wing of Hans Kelsen and became his assistant (1931-1933) at the Institute of International Law in Cologne, Germany. Hula's admiration for Kelsen and his work can be seen in the large volume of Kelsen materials collected in the Hula Papers, which include correspondence, notes and published materials.
In July of 1933, Hula married Annemarie Sporken, and for he next several years held posts with the Chambers of Labor in both Graz and Vienna, Austria. Shortly after the National Socialist takeover of Austria in 1938, Hula received an offer to join the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research, and on March 12, Hula left Austria with his wife and immigrated to the United States via Czechoslovakia, Switzerland and Great Britain.
Although Hula produced only one full-length book during his career (a collection of his essays), he wrote numerous essays on a variety of subjects: international law and international institutions, in particular the League of Nations and its successor the United Nations, national self-determination, punitive war and war crimes, as well as essays on the problems of individual countries, including Austria, Germany, Great Britain and many on the Soviet Union.
Erich Hula died in the Bronx, New York, on May 18, 1987.
Chronology of Events:
1900 May 27, born in Vienna, Austria.
1921-1924 Held a position at the Wiener Bankverein.
1924 Awarded Doctor of Law degree from University of Vienna, Austria.
1927-1930 Studied in England, France, and the United States under a Rockefeller Grant.
1931-1933 Assistant (to Hans Kelsen) at the Institute of International Law, Cologne, Germany.
1933 July 31, marriage to Annemarie Sporken.
1934-1937 Secretary, Chamber of Labor, Graz, Austria.
1937-1938 Secretary, Chamber of Labor, Vienna, Austria.
1937-1938 Member, Austrian Commission for the Codification of Labor Law.
1938 March 12, left Austria; emigrated to the United States via Czechoslovakia, Switzerland and Great Britain.
1938-1944 Associate Professor of Political Science, Graduate Faculty, New School for Social Research.
1941 Co-signer of founding resolution of Austrian Committee.
1942 Member of the advisory board of the Austrian National Committee and co-signer of proclamation of Military Committee for the Liberation of Austria.
1942 Became member of editorial board of the quarterly Social Research.
1944-1967 Professor of Political Science, Graduate Faculty, New School for Social Research.
1945 Became U.S. citizen, along with his wife.
1945-1948 Visiting Professor, Graduate School, Fordham University
1948-1950 Dean of the Graduate Faculty, New School for Social Research.
1953 Spring semester. Visiting Professor, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY.
1957-1958 Research Associate, The Johns Hopkins University, Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research, Washington, D.C.
1960 December 10, received the Große Goldene Ehrenzeichen für Verdienste um die Republik Österreich.
1967 Retirement from the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research.
1976 Renewal of Hula's doctoral degree by the University of Vienna.
1987 May 18, died in Bronx, New York.
Scope and Contents
A substantial portion of the Erich Hula Papers consists of his writings, both in typescript and published form. This includes his contributions to newspapers and journals, dating from the 1920s to 1984, and also contains extensive notes from his research as well as for courses taught primarily at the New School for Social Research. The collection also contains correspondence files and biographical documents, and a large collection of reprints (and some typescripts) sent to and collected by Hula of colleagues and other scholars, including Hans Kelsen, Hans Morgenthau, Leo Gross, Arnold Brecht and Kurt von Fritz.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Erich Hula in February 1978, with additional materials added in 1987.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Political Science; Military and Armed Conflict; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945--Atrocities.; International relations--Study and teaching.; Lecture notes; Manuscripts; Correspondence; Hula, Erich, 1900-; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.); United Nations; League of Nations
- Documents, Biographical Materials, 1900-1976; 1; 18 file folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a number of original documents from Austria, including birth, marriage and university documents, as well as correspondence, documents and several photographs associated with his long career as a member of the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research. Also present are correspondence and documents relating to Hula's Wiedergutmachung (restitution) and Austrian pension claims.
  - Austrian documents, 1900-1965 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 1)
    Includes copies of birth certificates, marriage certificate, university documents.
  - Doctoral degree from the University of Vienna, 1923 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 2)
  - New School for Social Research. Correspondence regarding appointments, salary, etc., 1938-1965 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 3)
  - Naturalization papers, 1944 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence concerning Hula's receipt of the Große Goldene Ehrenzeichen für Verdienste um die Republik Österreich, 1960 December 10 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 5)
  - Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) correspondence and documents, 1963-1974 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 6)
  - Wiedergutmachung correspondence (Robert M.W. Kempner), 1964-1975 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 7)
  - Chemical Bank, New York. Financial documents, 1969-1978 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 8)
  - Landesamt für Besoldung un Versorgung. Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 9)
  - Westdeutsche Landesbank, Cologne. Financial documents and correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 10)
  - Renewal of doctoral degree by University of Vienna, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 11)
  - Curriculum vitae, lists of publications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 12)
  - Articles about Hula in newspapers, etc., Undated (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 13)
  - Lexicon entries on Hula, Undated (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 14)
  - Address book, Undated (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 15)
  - Memberships, Undated (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 16)
  - Photographs of Hula, Undated; 2 (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 17)
  - Photographs of New School faculty members, Undated (Box 1 (1-Documents, Biographical Ma), Folder 18)
- Correspondence Files, 1927-1985; 2; 239 file folders
  This series contains primarily correspondence dealing with Hula's publications and includes correspondence with publishers, newspapers and periodicals, as well as colleagues. Individuals represented in the correspondence include colleagues at the New School for Social Research, such as Arnold Brecht, Eduard Heimann, Hans Simons and Hans Staudinger, as well as legal scholars and contemporaries such as Leo Gross, Hans Kelsen, Hans J. Morgenthau, Kurt Riezler, and Kurt von Fritz.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A - C, miscellaneous, unidentified, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)
  - Adamovich, Ludwig, 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 2)
  - Aftenposten (Oslo - Theo Findahl), 1960-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
  - America. National Catholic Weekly, 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
  - American Journal of International Law, 1959-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
  - Anderle, Othmar, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
  - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
  - Aufricht, Hans, 1945-1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
  - Austill, Allen, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
  - Beckerath, Thea von, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
  - Bellquist, Eric C. (Office of War Information), 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 11)
  - Berdahl, Clarence A., 1943-1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
  - Berger, Peter, 1944; 1967; 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
  - Borchard, Edwin, 1943-1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
  - Bradley, Phillips, 1939-1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
  - Brecht, Arnold, 1938-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
  - Brecht, Rolf, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
  - Brodersen, Arvid, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
  - Bucher, Alex J., 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 19)
  - Canadian Institute of International Affairs, 1952; 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
  - Carr, E.H., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 21)
  - Caspari, Henrik, 1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 22)
  - Christianity and Crisis (Wayne H. Cowan), 1961-1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
  - Claude, Inis L. Jr., 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 24)
  - Cobban, Alfred, 1944; 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
  - Coebergh, Elfreide & Jan, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 26)
  - Colegrove, Kenneth (The American Political Science Association), 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 27)
  - Collier's Encyclopedia (P.F. Collier & Son Corporation), 1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 28)
  - Cornides, Wilhelm, 1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 29)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 30)
  - Cropsey, Joseph, 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 31)
  - Cushman, Robert E., 1945; 1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 32)
  - D - F - miscellaneous & unidentified, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 33)
  - Daalder, Hans, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 34)
  - Deuticke, Franz, 1931 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 35)
  - Diamant, Alfred, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 36)
  - Dokumentationsarchiv des österreichischen Widerstands, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 37)
  - Drath, M., 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
  - Dumbarton Oaks article, 1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
  - Einaudi, Mario, 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 40)
  - Engelmann, Frederick, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
  - Eppel, Peter, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
  - Eschmann, I. T., 1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
  - Everett, John R., 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
  - Fay, Sidney B., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 45)
  - Fellner, Fritz, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - Flechtheim, Ossip K., 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 47)
  - Fletcher, H. George (Fordham University Press), 1975; Notes (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
  - Ford, (Father) George B., 1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
  - Forkosch, Morris D., 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 50)
  - Forum (Günther Nenning), 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
  - Frank, Julius, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
  - Freeman, Harrop A. (The Pacifist Research Bureau), 1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 53)
  - Freymond, Jacques, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
  - Fried, John H. E., 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 55)
  - Friedrich, Carl J., 1943-1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
  - Friesenhahn, Ernst, 1969; 1978-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
  - Fruehwirth, Guenter, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Funke, Gerhard, 1977-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
  - G - J - miscellaneous & unidentified, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Gambke, Gotthard, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
  - Gartz, Victor E., 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 62)
  - Gelber, Lionel, 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 63)
  - Germino, Dante, 1969-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 64)
  - Geyer, Herbert, 1980-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
  - Ginsburgs, George, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 66)
  - Goodrich, Leland M. (International Organization), 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
  - Gorbach, Alfons, 1961; 1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
  - Gottschalk, Anni, 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 69)
  - Graham, Robert A. (America. National Catholic Weekly), 1946-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 70)
  - Grant, J. A. C., 1944-1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Grathoff, Richard, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 72)
  - Greenbaum, Joseph, 1971; 1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Gross, Leo, 1950-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 74)
  - Haberda, Ernst, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1942; 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 76)
  - Hamburger, Ernst, 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 77)
  - Hamburger, Max, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 78)
  - Hans Kelsen-Institut, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 79)
  - Hartmann, Paul, 1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 80)
  - Hartnett, R. C., 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 81)
  - Hartshorne, Richard, 1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 82)
  - Hay, Marley F., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 83)
  - Heberle, Rudolf, 1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 84)
  - Heidenheim, Arnold, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 85)
  - Heimann, Eduard, 1946-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 86)
  - Hennis, Wilhelm, 1978-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 87)
  - Hermens, Ferdinand A., 1941; 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 88)
  - Herring, Pendleton, 1939 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 89)
  - Herz, John H., 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 90)
  - Holborn, Louise W., 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 91)
  - Hoppe, Irmgard, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 92)
  - Horikawa, Takeo, 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 93)
  - Hovde, Bryn J., 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 94)
  - Hugo von Hofmannsthal-Gesellschaft, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 95)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 96)
  - Hyde, Charles Cheney, 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 97)
  - Ingram, Elke, 1967-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 98)
  - Inman, Samuel Guy, 1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 99)
  - Inman, Walter G., 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 100)
  - Interpretation (Hilail Gildin), 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 101)
  - Jászi, Oscar, 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 102)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1951; 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 103)
  - Jonas, Hans, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 104)
  - The Journal of Poliltics, 1957; 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 105)
  - K - M - miscellaneous & unidentified, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 106)
  - Kann, Robert A., 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 107)
  - Karpovich, Michael, 1953 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 108)
  - Kelsen, Hans, 1961-1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 109)
  - Kempner, Benedicta Maria, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 110)
  - Kennan, George, 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 111)
  - Kirchheimer, Anne, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 112)
  - Kirk, Russell, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 113)
  - Klinghoffer, Hans, 1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 114)
  - Kohn, Hans, 1943-1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 115)
  - Kolnai, Aurel, 1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 116)
  - Konvitz, Milton R., 1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 117)
  - Krainer, Josef, 1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 118)
  - Kurtscheller, Friedrich, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 119)
  - Kutscher, Hans, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 120)
  - Laboulaye, François de, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 121)
  - LaFarge, John (America. National Catholic Weekly), 1943-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 122)
  - Lederer, Emil, 1938 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 123)
  - Lederer, Gertrude, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 124)
  - Lepsius, Rainer, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 125)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 126)
  - Lipsky, George A., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 127)
  - Loewenstein, Karl, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 128)
  - Löwith, Karl, 1952; 1970-1971; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 129)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 130)
  - Lowe, Adolph, 1973; 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 131)
  - Luckmann, Benita, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 132)
  - Ludz, Peter C., 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 133)
  - Lynd, Robert S., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 134)
  - Mansfield, Harvey, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 135)
  - Marshall, Charles Burton, 1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 136)
  - Matthiesen, Ulf, 1983; 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 137)
  - Mayer, Carl, 1970-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 138)
  - Meister, Richard, 1927 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 139)
  - Millet, Stanley, 1954; 1958; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 140)
  - Mintz, Walter, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 141)
  - Mire, Joseph, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 142)
  - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1942-1943; 1957; 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 143)
  - Mosely, Philip E., 1943; 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 144)
  - Mosler, Hermann, 1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 145)
  - Mundt, Karl E., 1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 146)
  - N - R - miscellaneous & unidentified, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 147)
  - Nef, John Ulric, 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 148)
  - Neisser, Charlotte (Mrs. Hans P), 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 149)
  - Nelson, Benjamin, 1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 150)
  - Noel, E., 1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 151)
  - Notter, Harley A., 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 152)
  - Nussbaum, Arthur, 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 153)
  - Parks, E. T., 1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 154)
  - Parsons, Geoffrey, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 155)
  - Pauli, Franca (Mrs. Wolfgang), 1958-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 156)
  - Peffer, Nathaniel, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 157)
  - Pekelis, Alex, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 158)
  - Pollock, James K., 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 159)
  - Potter, Lou (The Intellectual Exiles Project), 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 160)
  - Potter, Pitman B., 1945-1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 161)
  - Preuss, Lawrence, 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 162)
  - Pringham, Peter E., 1980-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 163)
  - Rabl, Kurt, 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 164)
  - Recasens-Siches, Luis, 1955; 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 165)
  - Redlich, Gertrud, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 166)
  - Reinhardt, Ursula, 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 167)
  - Religion in Life, 1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 168)
  - Renner, Karl, 1926 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 169)
  - Ridder, H., 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 170)
  - Rieber, Roger Alan, 1973-1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 171)
  - Riezler, Kurt, 1954-1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 172)
  - Robinson, Jacob, 1944; 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 173)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1954-1956 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 174)
  - Rommen, Heinrich, 1943 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 175)
  - Rossi, Mario, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 176)
  - Rudd, Herbert T., 1945 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 177)
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1943; 1961-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 178)
  - S - Z - miscellaneous & unidentified, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 179)
  - Schachter, Oscar, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 180)
  - Schätzel, Walter, 1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 181)
  - Schapiro, J. Salwyn, 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 182)
  - Scharizer, Martha, 1970-1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 183)
  - Scharizer, Ernst, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 183)
  - Schindler, Dietrich (Schweizer Monatshefte), 1960-1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 184)
  - Schüller, Richard, 1967-1971; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 185)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph A., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 186)
  - Schuschnigg, Kurt, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 187)